
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <channel>
   <title>Posts on table1.cc | Simple Creation of Summary Statistics for Research Papers</title>
   <link>https://www.table1.cc/blog/posts/</link>
   <description>Recent content in Posts on table1.cc | Simple Creation of Summary Statistics for Research Papers</description>
   <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
   <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2019 - table1.cc</copyright>
   <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 19:40:40 -0500</lastBuildDate>
   
       <atom:link href="https://www.table1.cc/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
   
     <item>
       <title>How We Handle Research Data to Ensure Privacy</title>
       <link>https://www.table1.cc/blog/posts/how-we-handle-research-data-to-ensure-privacy/</link>
       <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 19:40:40 -0500</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.table1.cc/blog/posts/how-we-handle-research-data-to-ensure-privacy/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Trust is a critical component of scientific collaboration including the use of research tools. In a previous post, we reviewed &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.table1.cc/blog/posts/ensuring-effective-encryption-on-table1cc/&#34;&gt;how table1.cc enforces encryption of all web traffic&lt;/a&gt;. In this post, we will review in detail how we handle the exchange of data in the table1.cc system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;submitting-data-to-table1cc&#34;&gt;Submitting data to table1.cc&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when you submit a data set via our website? After pasting data from a spreadsheet into the submit form and hitting &lt;em&gt;submit&lt;/em&gt;, your data is immediately encrypted. Table1.cc uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://letsencrypt.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let’s encrypt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; as our encryption certificate provider. This means that all data is transferred securely and cannot be accessed by any third party intermediary. The same happens with your desired settings you select when generating your Table 1 automatically (Figure 1, upper left).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.table1.cc/img/table1.cc-architecture.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Figure 1. Simplified scheme of the secure table1.cc website architecture. Communication between web browser, the Flask webserver, Python and tableone (within Heroku). See text for additional details.&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Figure 1. Simplified scheme of the secure table1.cc website architecture. Communication between web browser, the Flask webserver, Python and tableone (within Heroku). See text for additional details.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;research-data-processing-on-the-table1cc-application&#34;&gt;Research Data processing on the table1.cc application&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens when the encrypted data reaches the table1.cc server? Table1.cc runs on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.heroku.com&#34;&gt;Heroku platform&lt;/a&gt;, a cloud service that runs a &lt;em&gt;sandboxed&lt;/em&gt; environment (Figure 1, right outer rectangle). One of the characteristic design aspects of Heroku is that it uses a so-called &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;ephemeral&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; file system. &lt;em&gt;Ephemeral&lt;/em&gt; means that our underlying file system &lt;strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;cannot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; store &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; data permanently within this Heroku sandbox. To emphasize this point, the table1.cc application is not capable of permanently storing data which means that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;any data you submit to us will automatically be discarded once the task is completed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;generation-of--table-1--via-the-tableone-python-module&#34;&gt;Generation of &lt;em&gt;Table 1&lt;/em&gt; via the &lt;code&gt;tableone&lt;/code&gt; Python module&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next step, the SSL-encrypted data is received and process via a software called &lt;em&gt;Flask&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Flask&lt;/em&gt; is a Python web server framework which handles this communication between the user and application code. Because &lt;em&gt;Flask&lt;/em&gt; is pure Python code, communicating with other Python software modules is straightforward:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flask &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;translates&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; your data into a Python &lt;em&gt;data frame&lt;/em&gt;, a specialized data structure used in analytics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, it translates the preferences entered on the website into parameters for the Python/Pandas tableone package.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;rendering--table-1--within-the-browser-window&#34;&gt;Rendering &lt;em&gt;Table 1&lt;/em&gt; within the Browser window&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, Python and &lt;em&gt;tableone&lt;/em&gt; automatically generate the table summarizing you data of interest. Subsequently, this table is rendered into HTML, and then returned to the user. The user’s web browser then translates HTML into a human readable table on the website (Figure 1, lower left).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bottom-line&#34;&gt;Bottom Line&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table1.cc is designed from the bottom up to avoid storing any necessary data. This becomes most obvious by the complete absence of any database storage within its architecture. All data communication from and to the user is exclusively transmitted via enforced SSL encryption so you can feel confident that your research data remains absolutely confidential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can learn more about how automation with table1.cc can boost your research productivity &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.table1.cc/blog/posts/better-research-productivity-and-reproducibility-through-table1-automation&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are curious, give it a try &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.table1.cc&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and follow us on Twitter &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/table1cc&#34;&gt;@table1cc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Better Research Productivity and Reproducibility Through Table 1 Automation</title>
       <link>https://www.table1.cc/blog/posts/better-research-productivity-and-reproducibility-through-table1-automation/</link>
       <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 17:58:48 -0500</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.table1.cc/blog/posts/better-research-productivity-and-reproducibility-through-table1-automation/</guid>
       <description>&lt;meta name=&#34;twitter:image&#34; content=&#34;https://www.table1.cc/img/table1cc-interface-6.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is part of a series to review the inner workings of table1.cc, the website designed to help you handle the Table 1 generation process with more productivity and confidence. Here, we will briefly review the history of &lt;em&gt;Table 1 automation&lt;/em&gt; and discuss the considerations when applying it. We will then generate step-by-step a ‘Table 1’ using the table1.cc website and publicly available data. Finally, we will compare its characteristics in terms of ease and speed with alternative approaches using R/Python packages thus highlighting its potential utility in streamlining the analytic process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, in the following articles of the series, we will discuss the inner workings of the table1.cc web application during this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So let’s get started!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-brief-history-of-table-1-automation&#34;&gt;A brief history of Table 1 automation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On February 8, 2014 Kazuki Yoshida released &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/tableone/NEWS&#34;&gt;tableone version 0.1.0&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Tableone&lt;/em&gt; is a R package focused on Command Line Interface (CLI — a text-based display mode in which the user enters commands and data) users of the R programming language based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/kaz-yos/tableone&#34;&gt;Kazuki&#39;s Github Page&lt;/a&gt;. This R package has been highly influential, spawning a series of complimentary packages for the R programming language that can be accessed on the above mentioned website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 17, 2017 that development culminated in the release of a homonymous Python module with similar functionality by &lt;em&gt;Tom J Pollard, Alistair E W Johnson, Jesse D Raffa, Roger G Mark&lt;/em&gt; thus enabling automated Table 1 creation on the two main statistical programming universes: &lt;em&gt;Python/Pandas&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;R&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is notable that the original inspiration for the command line approaches came from a pioneering module &lt;em&gt;Deducer&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://crantastic.org/packages/Deducer&#34;&gt;https://crantastic.org/packages/Deducer&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Deducer&lt;/em&gt;, first released in 2009 by &lt;a href=&#34;https://crantastic.org/authors/880&#34;&gt;Ian Fellows&lt;/a&gt;, provided a Java-based graphical user interface aimed to make &lt;em&gt;R&lt;/em&gt; increasingly accessible to the general scientific community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;imageblock&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Solution&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Initial Release&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Platform&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Input&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Output&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deducer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;circa 2009&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R (programming language)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Graphical (Java)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R based&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;tableone (R)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;February 8, 2014&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R (programming language)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Command line based (R)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;R based&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;tableone (Python)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 17, 2017&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Python&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Command line based (R)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Python based&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.table1.cc&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;table1.cc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 22, 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graphical&lt;/strong&gt; (web based)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graphical&lt;/strong&gt; (web based)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Development of Table 1 automation solutions over time.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-utility-of-automation&#34;&gt;The utility of automation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To create the Table 1 sometimes it can be very time-consuming. Imagine if we have 10 variables (e.g. age, gender.. etc) for 3 groups, and for each variable we compute mean (standard deviation) and a number of participants (proportion); in the end, we have to fill 60 numbers in the table. Moreover, we usually export the table from R to Microsoft Word, and we can be prone to making mistakes if we’re copy/pasting.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;—Klodian Dhana (creator of datascienceplus.com)&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quote excellently sums up the important reasons for automation and the datascienceplus website does provide excellent resources to enable automated Table 1 generation via the use of &lt;em&gt;R&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;limits-of-command-line-approaches&#34;&gt;Limits of command line approaches&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the &lt;em&gt;datascienceplus.com&lt;/em&gt; website provides great resources for many important data science concepts, the following comments highlight the complicated nature of getting Table 1 automation to &lt;em&gt;just work&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.table1.cc/img/limitations-of-r-1.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Figure 1. An example of a data scientist with difficulties (source: datascienceplus.com website)&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Figure 1. An example of a data scientist with difficulties (source: datascienceplus.com website)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.table1.cc/img/limitations-of-r-syntax.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Figure 2. Another examples of complex syntax being a barrier to simple automation (source: datascienceplus.com)&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Figure 2. Another examples of complex syntax being a barrier to simple automation (source: &lt;a href=https://www.datascienceplus.com&gt;datascienceplus.com)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please keep in mind that this is focused to data scientists rather than a general scientific audience, so more accessible interfaces are needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The resulting table is functional, as seen below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.table1.cc/img/table1_screenshot-datascienceplus.jpg&#34;
         alt=&#34;Figure 3. The resulting Table using the traditional automation methods as discussed on datascienceplus.com (source: datascienceplus.com)&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Figure 3. The resulting Table using the traditional automation methods as discussed on datascienceplus.com (source: &lt;a href=https://datascienceplus.com/table-1-and-the-characteristics-of-study-population/&gt;datascienceplus.com)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-table1cc-is-different&#34;&gt;How table1.cc is different&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table1.cc simplifies and streamlines all steps of the process by omitting the need for complex syntax. Creating an automated &lt;em&gt;Table 1&lt;/em&gt; using table1.cc is easy using the following procedure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datascienceplus.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/dt_simulated.csv&#34;&gt;sample data set&lt;/a&gt; (courtesy of Klodian Dhana, datascienceplus.com)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copy the data set and paste contents (Figure 4)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.table1.cc/img/table1cc-interface-2.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Figure 4. The table1.cc landing page. Simply paste clipboard into the text box (red), then click on &amp;amp;lsquo;I pasted the spreadsheet data&amp;amp;rsquo; (green arrow)&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Figure 4. The table1.cc landing page. Simply paste clipboard into the text box (red), then click on &amp;lsquo;I pasted the spreadsheet data&amp;rsquo; (green arrow)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, you will advance to the following section and see a green notification &amp;ldquo;Table parsed successfully!&amp;rdquo; (Figure 5). On this page, tick all checkboxes, select the variable type as shown (green box)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.table1.cc/img/table1cc-interface-3.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Figure 5a. The table1.cc website after pasting and submitting the simulated data set. Select variables of interest in the green box. You can stratify your table by selecting a grouping variable (purple arrow)&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Figure 5a. The table1.cc website after pasting and submitting the simulated data set. Select variables of interest in the green box. You can stratify your table by selecting a grouping variable (purple arrow)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can now select the grouping variable. In the field &amp;ldquo;Select Grouping Variable&amp;rdquo; select &amp;ldquo;gender&amp;rdquo;. Then click on &amp;ldquo;Make Table 1&amp;rdquo; (Figure 5b, red arrow)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.table1.cc/img/table1cc-interface-4.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Figure 5b. Table1.cc allows to easily switch you grouping variable (red box). Confirm by clicking the button labeled &amp;amp;lsquo;Make Table 1!&amp;amp;rsquo; (red arrow)&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Figure 5b. Table1.cc allows to easily switch you grouping variable (red box). Confirm by clicking the button labeled &amp;lsquo;Make Table 1!&amp;rsquo; (red arrow)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After you clicked on this button, you will see the resulting table, already formatted, almost instantly. You may modify your options to perfect its appearance for your individual requirements. For instance, you may elect to calculate the appropriate p-Values and decide to omit the gender variable, since it is also the grouping variable. (Figure 5c)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.table1.cc/img/table1cc-interface-6.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Figure 5c. You can easily edit the appearance of the table by unchecking &amp;amp;lsquo;gender&amp;amp;rsquo;, checking &amp;amp;lsquo;calculate p-Values&amp;amp;rsquo; (purple boxes). Confirm your changes by clicking on &amp;amp;lsquo;Make Table 1&amp;amp;rsquo; once again (green arrow)&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Figure 5c. You can easily edit the appearance of the table by unchecking &amp;lsquo;gender&amp;rsquo;, checking &amp;lsquo;calculate p-Values&amp;rsquo; (purple boxes). Confirm your changes by clicking on &amp;lsquo;Make Table 1&amp;rsquo; once again (green arrow)&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You have successfully generated a Table 1 from scratch. Rather than the tedious manual process relying on repetitive copy and paste, your Table 1 is generated accurately and fast. Depending on you speed of mouse movement, you can complete all steps within less than 60 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.table1.cc/img/table1cc-interface-5.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Figure 6. The final Table 1, generated automatically from the sample data set&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Figure 6. The final Table 1, generated automatically from the sample data set&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bottom-line&#34;&gt;Bottom line&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do what you can do best, automate the rest!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;cite&gt;—Motto of table1.cc&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software utilities to automate Table 1 generation have advanced dramatically and now allow for reliable and intuitive interaction using platforms such was table1.cc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These new technologies allow to save time and effort and increased focus on your underlying research interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the following upcoming article of the series will focus on the inner workings of the table1.cc web application and the transformations along the way using the same example data set.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table1.cc is free of charge for researchers if you are curious. Give it a try &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.table1.cc&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and follow us on Twitter &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/table1cc&#34;&gt;@table1cc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>Ensuring Effective Encryption on table1.cc</title>
       <link>https://www.table1.cc/blog/posts/ensuring-effective-encryption-on-table1cc/</link>
       <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 19:19:24 -0500</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.table1.cc/blog/posts/ensuring-effective-encryption-on-table1cc/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Ensuring effective encryption is a central design requirement for the confidential handling of potentially sensitive research data. Enforcing encryption of transmitted content is therefore a key priority in table1cc&#39;s design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.table1.cc/img/https-example.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Figure 1. Table1.cc uses the https protocol exclusively&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Figure 1. Table1.cc uses the https protocol exclusively&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is to highlight the journey taken to enforce encryption on the table1.cc website. It serves to highlight our security efforts and ensure transparency, as well as help other website owners wanting to achieve enforced encryption when using Heroku and Flask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-websites-communicate-with-your-web-browser&#34;&gt;How websites communicate with your web browser:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are at least four ways to access any given website, here using “example.org” as a generic example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.example.org&#34;&gt;http://www.example.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.example.org&#34;&gt;http&lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;://www.example.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://example.org&#34;&gt;http://example.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://example.org&#34;&gt;http&lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;://example.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As web users, we expect any of these addresses to &lt;em&gt;“just work”&lt;/em&gt; at any time we type them into a browser and hit ENTER. Yet, on a technical level, these are four distinct web addresses that require individual routing and resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-significance-of--https--for-website-security&#34;&gt;The significance of &lt;em&gt;http&lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; for website security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main distinction from a security standpoint for the user is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the two &lt;em&gt;http&lt;em&gt;s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; addresses provide an encrypted protocol and therefore enhance safety&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The http (without s) addresses are un-encrypted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means as a website user, the use of &lt;em&gt;https&lt;/em&gt; is clearly superior and should be used whenever possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-ensure-that-https-is-used&#34;&gt;How to ensure that https is used&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, a website owner has at least three ways potential methods to ensure that all traffic is routed via &lt;em&gt;https&lt;/em&gt; via any of the following three layers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redirection on the DNS (so called Domain Name Server) (This is the server provider)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The web &lt;em&gt;server&lt;/em&gt; that is responsible for serving the website (such as Apache or nginx) can initiate the redirect to https&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The web application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;limitations-of-dns-1-layer-and-web-server-2-layer-approaches&#34;&gt;Limitations of DNS (1. Layer) and web server (2. Layer) approaches&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is generally recommended to use either the DNS server or web server layer should be used to ensure https redirects. However these two options come with  limitations that ultimately did not make them a viable option for table1.cc:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an increasingly relevant topic as the importance of https has been rising in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The table1.cc app runs on a web platform called Heroku a service platform that enables rapid development and improvement. Heroku is a Platform-as-a-service and comes with security enhancements out of the box. Despite these benefits, one challenge in enforcing encryption was of the virtual nature of this platform that limits the ability to access redirection. &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.heroku.com/NH44MODG/my-root-domain-isn-t-working-what-s-wrong&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Heroku documentation for details&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make matters even more complex, in 2017/2018 Heroku implemented changes to its infrastructure that simplified enabling encryption but rendered previous redirect methods ineffective. A large number of and search hits on Google, StackOverflow, and many other knowledge bases are unfortunately no longer applicable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To summarize:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To redirect traffic from one &lt;em&gt;https&lt;/em&gt; to another &lt;em&gt;https&lt;/em&gt; domain consistently, the DNS server would require access to a separate https certificate for the address (given that all addresses are handled separately) Since DNS servers do not usually have access to a given website’s encryption certificate, the redirect attempt fails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The web server level requires access to the web server. However, Heroku utilizes an ‘ephemeral’ file system and other restrictions, that while generally advantageous preclude this option limits the ability to&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-ensure-consistent-https-encryption-with-heroku-and-flask-in-2020&#34;&gt;How to ensure consistent https encryption with Heroku and Flask in 2020&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the solution involved rerouting all web traffic on the application level (3rd layer). While this is somewhat more computationally intensive (and therefore more costly), this was ultimately the preferred because it is the safest method for our users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;here-is-how-the-implementation-works-in-case-this-is-useful-for-other-heroku-and-flask-users&#34;&gt;Here is how the implementation works in case this is useful for other Heroku and Flask users:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on a StackOverflow post by user &lt;em&gt;Danilo Bargen&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/9766134/how-do-i-redirect-to-the-www-version-of-my-flask-site-on-heroku&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
The code was updated to reflect changes in Python3:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;table style=&#34;border-spacing:0;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;width:auto;overflow:auto;display:block;&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td style=&#34;vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f&#34;&gt; 1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f&#34;&gt; 2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f&#34;&gt; 3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f&#34;&gt; 4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f&#34;&gt; 5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f&#34;&gt; 6
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f&#34;&gt; 7
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f&#34;&gt; 8
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f&#34;&gt; 9
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f&#34;&gt;10
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;vertical-align:top;padding:0;margin:0;border:0;;width:100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python3&#34; data-lang=&#34;python3&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;from&lt;/span&gt; urllib.parse &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; urlparse, urlunparse

&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;@app&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;before_request
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;redirect_nonwww&lt;/span&gt;():
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;Redirect non-www requests to www.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
    urlparts &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; urlparse(request&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;url)
    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; urlparts&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;netloc &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;example.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;:
        urlparts_list &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; list(urlparts)
        urlparts_list[&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;] &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;www.example.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; redirect(urlunparse(urlparts_list), code&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;301&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;redirection-scheme-on-table1cc&#34;&gt;Redirection scheme on table1.cc&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This table shows the current routing scheme for the four possible combinations of https and www / non-www URLs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Entered address&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Redirects to&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://table1.cc&#34;&gt;http://table1.cc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.table1.cc&#34;&gt;https://www.table1.cc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.table.cc&#34;&gt;http://www.table.cc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.table1.cc&#34;&gt;https://www.table1.cc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.table1.cc&#34;&gt;https://www.table1.cc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.table1.cc&#34;&gt;https://www.table1.cc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://table1.cc&#34;&gt;https://table1.cc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.table1.cc&#34;&gt;https://www.table1.cc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table 1: How redirects on table1.cc enforce reliable encryption&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bottom-line&#34;&gt;Bottom line&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter which of the four addresses is entered when using table1.cc: All traffic to and from table1.cc is encrypted via https/SSL so you can rest assured your data is safe. To verify that encryption is active, you can look for the &amp;ldquo;lock&amp;rdquo; symbol in the taskbar of your web browser as seen in Fig 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expect more updates on new table1.cc features in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are curious, give it a try &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.table1.cc&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and follow us on Twitter &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/table1cc&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
     <item>
       <title>table1.cc | Simple Creation of Summary Statistics for Research Papers</title>
       <link>https://www.table1.cc/blog/posts/simple-creation-of-table1-summary-statistics-for-research-papers-using-table1cc/</link>
       <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 18:51:01 -0500</pubDate>
       
       <guid>https://www.table1.cc/blog/posts/simple-creation-of-table1-summary-statistics-for-research-papers-using-table1cc/</guid>
       <description>&lt;p&gt;Generating summary statistics is a common task in research and often requires iterative refinements. In this post we will demonstrate how to conveniently generate a &lt;em&gt;Table 1&lt;/em&gt; used for research papers in an automated fashion. We will be using public data from a clinical trial by &lt;em&gt;Vickers et al.&lt;/em&gt; (2004) which was published in the British Medical Journal (BMJ) on the use of acupuncture as a therapy for chronic headache. The PDF is available for download for free at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bmj.com/content/328/7442/744.full.pdf&#34;&gt;BMJ website (link)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is customary, the authors provide a &lt;em&gt;Table 1&lt;/em&gt; featuring baseline characteristics of the treatment and control groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://www.table1.cc/img/table1.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Figure 1: Table 1 showing the baseline characteristics of a 2004 clinical trial by Vickers et al. which we will use as an example for this tutorial&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Figure 1: &lt;em&gt;Table 1&lt;/em&gt; showing the baseline characteristics of a 2004 clinical trial by &lt;em&gt;Vickers et al.&lt;/em&gt; which we will use as an example for this tutorial&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A copy of the raw trial data is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://trialsjournal.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1745-6215-7-15#Sec18&#34;&gt;here (link)&lt;/a&gt; on the Springer website (Excel File Format).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this data set we will walk through the steps on how to create a &lt;em&gt;Table 1&lt;/em&gt; automatically, by making use of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.table1.cc&#34;&gt;www.table1.cc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Let&#39;s get started!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-download-the-sample-trial-data&#34;&gt;1. Download the sample trial data&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://trialsjournal.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1745-6215-7-15#Sec18&#34;&gt;https://trialsjournal.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/1745-6215-7-15#Sec18&lt;/a&gt; to download the trial raw data (excel format) or use the direct link here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://static-content.springer.com/esm/art%3A10.1186%2F1745-6215-7-15/MediaObjects/13063_2006_152_MOESM1_ESM.xls&#34;&gt;13063_2006_152_MOESM1_ESM.xls)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-select-the-data-of-interest&#34;&gt;2. Select the data of interest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the Excel file with MS Excel, LibreOffice or Google Docs
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Table 1 in the trial is based only on patients that are listed as &lt;em&gt;“completers”&lt;/em&gt;. (Fig. 2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you wish to recreate the exact same Table 1 select patients that are &lt;em&gt;“completers”&lt;/em&gt;: In the tab &amp;lsquo;Data&amp;rsquo;, sort for &amp;lsquo;completers&amp;rsquo; and select all rows in which completer is ‘1’. This should be the case for 302 rows (including the header row).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feel free to use a different subset of the data set or your own data set if you would like to experiment with that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy the rows of interest into the clipboard by either pressing &lt;em&gt;control+c&lt;/em&gt; or right clicking on the selection and selecting copy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.table1.cc/img/select_rows.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Figure 2. Selecting all rows (cases) who completed the 2004 clinical trial&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Figure 2. Selecting all rows (cases) who completed the 2004 clinical trial&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-go-to-table1cchttpwwwtable1cc-and-paste-the-content-of-the-clipboard&#34;&gt;3. Go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.table1.cc&#34;&gt;table1.cc&lt;/a&gt; and paste the content of the clipboard&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right-click on the text field on the starting page and select &lt;em&gt;paste&lt;/em&gt; (Fig. 3; orange box). Alternatively, you can press &lt;em&gt;control + v&lt;/em&gt; to paste the file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, click on &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;I pasted the spreadsheet data&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; (Fig. 3; red arrow)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.table1.cc/img/paste-data-annotated.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Figure 3. How to paste spreadsheet data into table1.cc&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Figure 3. How to paste spreadsheet data into table1.cc&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-select-variables-of-interest-and-variable-types&#34;&gt;4. Select variables of interest and variable types&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should see a message &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Table parsed successfully&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; appear in a green box (Fig. 4)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To recreate the original Table 1, check &lt;em&gt;age&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;sex&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;migraine&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;chronicity&lt;/em&gt; as &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;variables of interest&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feel free to experiment with other variables. For the example data set, their meaning can be found in the Excel file in the &lt;em&gt;Description of Variables&lt;/em&gt; tab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;age&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, leave &lt;em&gt;continuous&lt;/em&gt;. For &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;sex&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;migraine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, select &lt;em&gt;categorical&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.table1.cc/img/data-parsed.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Figure 4. Selecting variables of interest and variable types&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Figure 4. Selecting variables of interest and variable types&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-select-the-grouping-variable-and-confirm-to-create-the-table&#34;&gt;5. Select the grouping variable and confirm to create the table&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;‘grouping variable’&lt;/em&gt; stratifies the resulting table by a certain characteristic.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To recreate the original &lt;em&gt;Table 1&lt;/em&gt;, select &lt;em&gt;group&lt;/em&gt; (which distinguishes between intervention and control patients).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;switch group order&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; to have the intervention group (1) appear before the controls (0)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scroll down and click the &lt;em&gt;“Make Table 1!”&lt;/em&gt; button&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scroll down again and your &lt;em&gt;Table 1&lt;/em&gt; with the selected variables of interests and the appropriate measures (mean, standard deviation, percentages) appears (Figure 5)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.table1.cc/img/result.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Figure 5. Selecting variables of interest and variable types for your table 1&#34;/&gt; &lt;figcaption&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Figure 5. Selecting variables of interest and variable types for your table 1&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voilà, you just created summary statistics, fast and efficient !&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-adjust-and-fine-tune-formatting&#34;&gt;6. Adjust and Fine tune formatting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experiment with additional variables of interest, adding p-values, etc.;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is now very simple to add p values, missing values, and fine-tune the table to you needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can also explore other grouping options to help understand your data
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selections of variables can be adjusted quickly, as the settings will carry forward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The caveat of the authors of the tableone Python package always applies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We encourage the use of tableone alongside other methods of descriptive statistics and, in particular, visualization to ensure appropriate data handling. [&amp;hellip;] Guidance should be sought from a statistician when using &lt;code&gt;tableone&lt;/code&gt; for a research study, especially prior to submitting the study for publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try out simple and efficient creation of your &lt;em&gt;Table 1&lt;/em&gt; by applying this tutorial at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.table1.cc&#34;&gt;https://www.table1.cc&lt;/a&gt; !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Follow us on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitter.com/table1cc&#34;&gt;Twitter (@table1cc)&lt;/a&gt;  to stay up to date with new features or submit requests or questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
     </item>
   
 </channel>
</rss>
